12manage.com 2015-12-27

# 12manage - Privacy and Cookie Policy

### Introduction:

The mission of 12manage is to facilitate learning and sharing management methods, know-how, skills and experiences among management professionals. We work to fulfill this mission by helping you and millions of other management professionals learn, exchange ideas, meet, make deals, find opportunities or employees, work, and make decisions in a global network.

Being part of 12manage means sharing information about yourself with other management professionals, communicating with them, as well as working privately on your own. By default, your account is set up to share the information that we have found the vast majority of our Users are interested in sharing. But the amount and type of information you decide to share, and with whom you share it, is up to you.

Here are the three main types of information on 12manage:

  * Information about yourself that you share. This is the information that other management professionals and companies see about you. This includes your profile and your contributions to discussions in a forum, Special Interest Group, Community, or other community features 12manage offers. You have control over what you share, and you can update information at any time.
  * Communication. We help you communicate with other management professionals. Some of this is one-to-one, some of it is in groups, and some of it is public discussion. You decide how much or how little you wish to communicate to individuals or groups.
  * Private activity. We also provide tools that you can use privately on 12manage (for example to personalize your management start page with your own links, notes and files.) This information is private and we don't share or distribute this to others on the website.

Of course, maintaining your trust is our top concern, so we adhere to the following principles to protect your privacy:

  * We do not rent, sell, or otherwise provide your personally identifiable information to third parties for marketing purposes.
  * We do not share any information you have not chosen to display on your 12manage profile to other parties, unless compelled by law, or as necessary to enforce our Terms of Service or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of 12manage, its Users, and the public.
  * All information that you provide will be protected with industry standard protocols and technology.

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, or by email, or by means of a notice on our home page. By continuing to use the 12manage service after notice of changes has been sent to you or published on the 12manage website, you are consenting to the changes.

Please read this policy and send us questions, concerns and suggestions at [info@12manage.com](mailto:info@12manage.com).

### What 12manage’s Privacy Policy Covers:

  1. Information we receive.
  2. How we use your information.
  3. Your information choices.
  4. Your obligations as a User.
  5. Updates to this policy.
  6. How we protect information.
  7. How to contact us.

  1. **Information we receive**

The mission of 12manage is to facilitate learning and sharing management methods, know-how, skills and experiences among management professionals. To achieve this mission, 12manage makes services available through our website, mobile phones, and other electronic or traditional media to enable professionals to learn, exchange ideas, develop, maintain and enhance a network of contacts, seek experts and consultants, create, share, and distribute information in collaboration with one another ("Services"). By joining 12manage, you voluntarily and willingly provide us certain information, including personally identifiable information, which we collect in order to provide the Services. If you have any hesitation about providing information to us and/or having your information displayed on the 12manage website or otherwise used in any manner permitted in this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Services, you should not become a member of the 12manage community; and, if you are already a member, you should terminate your account.

We collect your personal information in the following ways: 

    1. Registration

In order to become a User, you must provide us the following information to create an account: gender, name, profession and email address. You acknowledge that this information is personal to you, and by creating an account on 12manage, you allow others, including 12manage, to identify you.

    2. Profile Information

Once you become a User, you may provide additional information on your [Personal Page](http://www.12manage.com/profile.asp) describing your profile, including your interests, professional experiences, educational background, messages from other users, group memberships, and objectives. Providing additional information about yourself beyond what is minimally required at registration is entirely up to you, but providing additional information enables you to derive more benefit from 12manage and your professional network by helping you build and leverage your professional network and facilitating your search for professional resources, information, and new opportunities. Any information you provide at registration or in the Profile section may be used by 12manage as described in the Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy, including for the purpose of serving advertisements through the service. If you decide not to share certain information, you may not receive the full benefit of being a 12manage User.

    3. Contacts Information

In order to connect with others on 12manage, you may use the Services to send messages either to their 12manage profiles or email addresses if they are not Users. The names and email addresses of people you contact will be used to send your messages and reminders as well as to allow 12manage to help expand your network. When you send a message to connect to another User, that User will not have access to your email address because it is encrypted and not displayed in the invitation.

You may also choose to manually enter or upload data about your contacts to the "Invitations" section of your 12manage home page. Information entered into Invitations is only viewable by you. By providing email addresses or other information of non-Users to 12manage, you represent that you have authority to do so. All information that you enter or upload about your contacts will be covered by the Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy and will enable us to provide customized services such as suggesting people to connect with on 12manage.

    4. Customer Service

We may collect information through the 12manage website or through our customer service department in order to, among other things, accurately categorize and respond to customer inquiries and investigate breaches of our terms.

    5. Site Usage

We may collect information about the fact that you use certain features and functionality of 12manage, interact with third party applications, click on ads, or participate in research initiatives like polling and surveys on 12manage.

    6. Cookies

Like most websites, we use cookies and web log files to track site usage and trends, to improve the quality of our service, to customize your experience on 12manage, as well as to deliver third-party advertising to Users both on and off the 12manage site. A cookie is a tiny data file that resides on your computer, mobile phone, or other device, and allows us to recognize you as a User when you return to the 12manage website using the same computer and web browser. You can remove or block cookies using the settings in your browser, but this will impact your ability to use 12manage. One type of cookie, known as a "persistent" cookie, may be set once you’ve logged in to your 12manage account. The next time you visit the 12manage website, the persistent cookie will allow us to remember you as an existing User so you will not need to log in before using the Services. In order to change certain information (like your password), however, you must log in securely again with your password even if your computer contains your persistent cookie. Another type of cookie, called a "session" cookie, is used to identify a particular visit to the 12manage website. Session cookies expire after a certain amount of time or when you close your web browser.

In the course of serving advertisements or optimizing the Services to our Users, we may allow authorized third parties to place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser. Any information provided to third parties through cookies will not be personally identifiable but may provide general segment information (e.g., your industry or geography, career field, or information about your professional or educational background) for greater customization of your user experience. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. 12manage does not store unencrypted personally identifiable information in the cookies.

    7. Advertising

To support the Services we provide at no cost to our Users, as well as provide a more relevant and useful experience for our Users, we serve our own ads and also allow third party advertisements on the site. These advertisements are targeted and served to Users, by both 12manage and other companies, called ad networks. Ad networks include third party ad servers, ad agencies, ad technology vendors and research firms.

Advertisements on 12manage may be targeted to Users who fit a certain general profile category (e.g., marketing managers in Amsterdam") or may be based on anonymized information inferred from a User’s profile (e.g., industry, gender, age, nationality, or other aspects of your life) in addition to a User’s use of the 12manage site. 12manage does not provide personally identifiable information to any third party ad network.

    8. Log files, IP addresses and information about your computer and mobile device

Due to the communications standards on the internet, when you visit the 12manage website we automatically receive the URL of the site from which you came and the site to which you are going when you leave 12manage. 12manage also receives the internet protocol ("IP") address of your computer (or the proxy server you use to access the World Wide Web), your computer operating system and type of web browser you are using, email patterns, mobile device operating system (if you are accessing 12manage using a mobile device), as well as the name of your ISP or your mobile carrier. We use this information to analyze overall trends to help improve the service. The linkage between your IP address and your personally identifiable information is not shared with third parties without your permission, except as described in Section 2.J ("Compliance with Legal Process"), below.

    9. Linked Accounts

If you link your 12manage account to another account or service, or use other, third-party sites or services in conjunction with your 12manage account, we may collect information related to your use of third party sites and services accessed through 12manage or when you access 12manage through a third-party site or service.

    10. Rights to Access, Correct and Eliminate Information About You

You have a right to access, modify, correct and eliminate the data you supplied to 12manage. If you update any of your information, we may keep a copy of the information that you originally provided to us in our archives for uses documented in this policy. You may request deletion of your information at any time by [contacting 12manage customer service](mailto:info@12manage.com). We will respond to your request within 30 days.

  2. **How we use your information**

    1. Consent to 12manage Processing Information About You

The information you provide to 12manage may reveal, or allow others to identify, your nationality, ethnic origin, religion, gender, age, geography, or other aspects of your private life. By providing information to us for the purposes of creating your User account or adding any additional details to your 12manage profile, you are expressly and voluntarily accepting the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy and 12manage’s Terms of Service that allow 12manage to process information about you. Supplying information to 12manage, including any information deemed "sensitive" by applicable law, is entirely voluntary on your part. You have the right to withdraw your consent to 12manage’s collection and processing of your information at any time, in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Service, by changing your [preferences](http://www.12manage.com/login.asp), or by terminating your account, but please note that your withdrawal of consent will not be retroactive.

    2. 12manage Communications

As described in the Terms of Service, we will communicate with you through email and notices posted on the 12manage website, email messages, messages on your personal page, or through other means available through the service, including mobile text messages. We may send you a series of emails that help inform new Users about the features of the Services, and we will also send you service messages relating to the functioning of the Services. We may also send you messages with promotional information directly or on behalf of our partners, unless you have opted out of receiving such information.

You can change your e-mail and contact preferences at any time by logging into your account and changing your [preferences](http://www.12manage.com/login.asp) related to your email notification (newsletter) choices.

Please be aware that you cannot opt-out of receiving service messages from 12manage.

    3. User Communications

Many communications you initiate through 12manage (e.g., an invitation sent to a non-User) will list your name in the header of the message. Your contact information will only be shared with another User if both of you are Members of 12manage.

    4. Customized Content

We use information provided to us (or to third parties with whom it offers combined services) to customize your experience on our website. For example, when you login to your account, we will display the names of new Members who have recently joined your Special Interest Group and recent forum comments and reactions in your interest area.

    5. Sharing Information with Third Parties

12manage takes the privacy of our Users very seriously, and we do not sell, rent, or otherwise provide your personally identifiable information to third parties for marketing purposes. Further, we will only share your personally identifiable information with third parties to carry out your instructions or to provide the Services or information unless compelled by law, or as necessary to enforce our Terms of Service or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of 12manage, its Users, and the public. For example, we use a payment processing company to bill Users for subscription fees. These third parties do not retain, share, or store any personally identifiable information except to provide these services, and they are bound by confidentiality agreements limiting the use of your information.

We also offer a "public profile" feature that allows Users to publish portions of their 12manage profile to the public internet. This public profile is what search engines will display when someone searches for your name. Users may opt-out of this feature by editing their [profile](http://www.12manage.com/profile.asp); however, 12manage does not warrant how often third-party search engines will update their caches, which may contain old public profile information.

We may provide aggregated anonymous data about the usage of the Services to third parties for purposes that we deem, in our sole discretion, to be appropriate, including to prospective advertisers on 12manage.

    6. Working with Third Parties to Offer Services.

We may collaborate with third parties to offer services and functionality using 12manage developer tools such as application programming interfaces ("APIs"). These third parties are either partners ("12manage Partners") with whom we have negotiated an agreement to provide services ("Combined Services"), or developers ("Platform Developers") who have agreed to our API terms in our developer signup flow to build applications ("Platform Applications"). Both the negotiated agreements and our API terms and conditions contain restrictions on access, storage and use of your information.

If you choose to use Combined Services or a Platform Application, you may be asked to confirm acceptance of the privacy policy and/or Terms of Service of the 12manage Partner or Platform Developer, which have not necessarily been reviewed or approved by 12manage. It is your choice whether or not to make use of Combined Services or Platform Applications and whether to proceed under any third party terms.

Also, despite our agreements and technical steps taken to restrict access to and avoid possible misuse of information we may not screen or audit all Combined Services or Platform Applications. We also cannot guarantee that any 12manage Partner or Platform Developer will abide by our agreement. You agree that your use of Combined Services or Platform Applications is on an "as is" basis and without any warranty.

If you, members of your network, or other Users of 12manage use or interact with any Combined Service or Platform Application, the 12manage Partner or Platform Developer may access and share certain information about you with others, such as your profile information and information visible only to 12manage members. This includes information about your connections by virtue of you being connected to others. However, because a Combined Service or Platform Application can make calls on behalf of the User interacting with it to access non-public information, the level of detail accessible by the Combined Service or Platform Application through 12manage is constrained by the same settings that govern visibility of your data to that User on 12manage. For example, assuming you have not already given a Platform Developer’s application permission to access your information, your non-public profile information should not be visible to someone using the same Platform Application if it is not otherwise accessible to that person on 12manage.

Please also note that because of our relationship with certain 12manage Partners and Platform Developers, permission to access certain account information may be automatically granted to provide the combined services or functionality. You can request a list of current 12manage Partners [here](mailto:info@12manage.com).

To revoke permission granted to a Combined Service or Platform Application at any time, please visit the [preferences page](http://www.12manage.com/login.asp). If the relevant Platform Developer or Application, or 12manage Partner is not listed under Authorized Applications, go directly to the Application Details page for the Platform Application you wish to uninstall. To report any suspected misuse of information, contact 12manage’s customer service. 12manage is not responsible for your use of or inability to use any Combined Service or Platform Application, including the content, accuracy, or reliability of applications and the privacy practices or other policies of 12manage Partners or Platform Developers.

    7. Polls and Surveys

Polls and Surveys may be conducted by 12manage, 12manage Users or third parties. As a User, you may be invited to participate in polls and surveys from the 12manage website. Your selection may be random, or it may be based on your non-personally identifiable information, such as job title, language, geography, company size and/or industry. Whether or not you decide to participate in a poll or survey is completely up to you.

After you complete a poll, you will be given access to the aggregate responses of the poll on a results page. Some third parties may target advertisements to you on the results page based on your answers in the poll. Further, 12manage or third parties may follow up with you unless you have opted out this.

We may use third parties to deliver incentives to you to participate in surveys or polls. If the delivery of incentives requires your contact information, you may be asked to provide personally identifiable information to the third party fulfilling the incentive offer, which will only be used for the purpose of delivering incentives and/or verifying your contact information. It is up to you whether you provide this information, or whether you desire to take advantage of an incentive.

We will not disclose any personally identifiable information to any third parties in connection with the conduct of any polls or surveys. Your consent to use any personally identifiable information for the purposes set forth in the poll or survey will be explicitly requested by the party conducting it.

    8. Search

We offer search services to help find information and learn more about other Users (for example, you can search for Users (Members) with particular expertise or experience). 12manage search also allows Users to find companies, and contributions to the community aspects of the 12manage Services, such as our forums that will help Users more effectively use 12manage and expand their network. We use information from User profiles and contributions to forums to inform and refine our search service.

    9. Forums, Special Interest Groups, Communities, Views, and other Services

If you post on the 12manage forums, participate in 12manage Special Interest Groups or Communities, publish your views, or use similar 12manage services, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you choose to provide there can be read, collected, or used by other Users of these services, as well as Platform Developers and other third parties, and could be used to contact you. 12manage is not responsible for the information you choose to submit in these services.

    10. Compliance with Legal Process

It is possible that we may need to disclose personal information, profile information and/or information about your activities as a 12manage User when required by subpoena or other legal process, or if 12manage has a good faith belief that disclosure is necessary to (a) investigate, prevent or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities or to assist government enforcement agencies; (b) to enforce the Terms of Service, to investigate and defend ourselves against any third party claims or allegations, or to protect the security or integrity of our site; and/or (c) to exercise or protect the rights, property or personal safety of 12manage, our Users, employees, or others.

    11. Disclosures to others

We may also disclose your personal information and other information you provide to another third party as part of a reorganization or a sale of the assets of 12manage BV, a subsidiary or division. Any third party to which 12manage transfers or sells 12manage’s assets will have the right to continue to use the personal and other information that you provide to us.

  3. **Your information choices**

    1. Accessing and Changing Your Account Information

You can review the personal information you provided to us and make any desired changes to the information you publish, or to the settings for your 12manage account including your email and contact preferences, at any time in your [preferences](http://www.12manage.com/login.asp) on the 12manage website. Please be aware that even after your request for a change is processed, 12manage may, for a time, retain residual information about you in its backup and/or archival copies of its database.

    2. Default Settings

Because the mission of 12manage is is to make organizational and management knowledge available globally as well as to connect management professionals, we have established what we believe to be reasonable default settings that we have found most management professionals desire. Because Users may use and interact with 12manage in a variety of ways, and because those uses may change over time, we designed our settings to provide our users granular control over the information they share. We encourage our Users to review their account settings and adjust them in accordance with their preferences.

12manage accounts are also defaulted to allow Users to be contacted to participate in polls, surveys and partner advertising.

    3. Terminating Your Account

You can end your account through the 12manage site. If you terminate your 12manage account, we will remove your profile and other personally identifiable information from our publicly viewable database. If you terminate your account, we have no obligation to retain your information, and may delete any or all of your account information without liability. However, we may retain certain data contributed by you if 12manage believes it may be necessary to prevent fraud or future abuse, or for legitimate business purposes, such as analysis of aggregated, non-personally identifiable data, account recovery, or if required by law. 12manage may also retain and use your information if necessary to provide the Services to other Users. For example, just as an email you may send to another person through an email service provider resides in that person’s inbox even after you delete it from your sent files or close your account, emails or messages you send on 12manage to other Users, as well as your contributions you made to 12manage forums, expert tips and resources will remain visible to others after you have ended your account. Similarly, other information you have shared with others, or that other Users have copied, may also remain visible. 12manage disclaims any liability in relation to the deletion or retention (subject to the terms herein) of information or any obligation not to delete the information. 12manage does not control when search engines update their cache, which may contain certain public profile information that has since been removed from 12manage’s publicly viewable database.

    4. Memorializing Accounts

If we learn that a User is deceased, we may memorialize the User’s account. In these cases we may restrict profile access, remove messaging functionality, and terminate an account if we receive a formal request from the User’s next of kin or other proper legal request to do so.

  4. **Your obligations as a User**

As a User, you have certain obligations to other Users. Some of these obligations are imposed by applicable law and regulations, and others have become commonplace in user-friendly communities of like-minded members such as 12manage: 

    * You must, at all times, abide by the terms and conditions of the then-current Privacy Policy and Terms of Service. This includes respecting all intellectual property rights that may belong to third parties (such as trademarks or photographs).
    * You must not download or otherwise disseminate any information that may be deemed to be injurious, violent, offensive, racist or xenophobic, or which may otherwise violate the purpose and spirit of 12manage and its communities of Users.
    * You must not provide to 12manage and/or other Users information that you believe might be injurious or detrimental to your person or to your professional or social status.
    * You must keep your username and password confidential and not share it with others.

Any violation of these guidelines may lead to the restriction, suspension or termination of your account at the sole discretion of 12manage. 

  5. **Updates to this policy**

    1. Children and Minors

Children are not eligible to use our service and we ask that minors (under the age of 18) do not submit any personal information to us or use the service.

We have self-certified our privacy practices as consistent with U.S. - E.U. Safe Harbor principles: Notice, Choice, Onward Transfer, Access and Accuracy, Security, Data Integrity and Enforcement.

Please note that by becoming a User, you have given us your express and informed consent to transfer the data that you provide to us to the Netherlands and to process it in the Netherlands.

If Users have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, you should first contact 12manage by email at [info@12manage.com](mailto:info@12manage.com). If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or it is not satisfactorily addressed, you may raise your complaint by fax at +31-30-2254-788.

    2. Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy at any time, with or without advance notice. In the event there are significant changes in the way we treat your personally identifiable information, or in the Privacy Policy document itself, we will display a notice on the 12manage website or send you an email, as provided for above. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information that 12manage has about you and your account.

Using the 12manage Services after a notice of changes has been sent to you or published on our site shall constitute consent to the changed terms or practices.

  6. **How we protect information**

In order to help secure your personal information, access to your data on 12manage is password-protected, and sensitive data (such as payment information) is protected by SSL encryption when it is exchanged between your web browser and our payment provider. To protect any data you store on our servers, 12manage also regularly checks its system for possible vulnerabilities and attacks, and we use a secure data center. However, since the internet is not a 100% secure environment, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to 12manage. There is no guarantee that information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. It is your responsibility to protect the security of your login information. Please note that emails, instant messaging, and similar means of communication with other Users of 12manage are not encrypted, and we strongly advise you not to communicate any confidential information through these means. 

  7. **How to contact us**

If you have any questions or comments please email us at [info@12manage.com](mailto:info@12manage.com) or contact us at:

12manage BV

Attention of: Privacy and Cookie Policy Issues

Obrechtlaan 14

3723KC Bilthoven

The Netherlands
